ASIF IQBAL AHMED

Contact No.: +91 9594854281 Email Id: asifat51@gmail.com

SUMMARY

An astute Sales and Marketing Professional with 12+ years of experience in Devising and Implementation of Innovative Strategies, Market Research, Competitor Analysis, Market Penetration, and Spreading of Distribution Network. Expert use of technology to reduce paperwork and effective Organizational Skills. Excellent communication and interpersonal skills.

KEY STRENGTHS

- Strategic Planning
- Innovative and Creative Solutions
- Market Penetration & Expansion
- Organizational Skills
- Dealer DistributionNetwork

- Payment Collection
- Sales Promotion
- Competitor Analysis
- ❖ Intelligent Use of Technology
- Excellent Communication Skills

CAREER OVERVIEW

I am a proficient Sales & Marketing Professional with more than 10 years of experience in the various fields of New Market Penetration, Market Expansion and Sales Promotion. I have earned praises for the increase in sales which I brought in through my expert planning and effective implementation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

1. STAG INDIA LTD

1st of May 2015 to till date

Designation: SENIOUR Sales Manager WEST INDIA

Posted – Mumbai

Company Profile :- www.stagindia.com

Product Deal: PERFORMANCE FITNESS EQUIPMENT

Current CTC – 7.75 Lakhs (Indian Currency)

Job Responsibilities:

- Develop dealer distribution network and introduce new dealer from Sports and Footwear industries to boost up market as per needed.
- Responsible for primary sales and collection target for the company.
- ❖ Focus on Pimery for Distributor as well treachery sale for Dealer.
- Coordination with Company for DFS (Demand for Sales) / Material Movement till Distributor Goodown
- ❖ Arrange sales promotion activities to directly attract customers. (ATL Activities)
- Reduced paperwork by integrating paperless office techniques with SAP Technology and Smart Phone
- Keeping track of competitors activities

2. PUMA INDIA LTD . APRIL 2015

DEC 2013 TO 30TH

Designation: Bussiness Manager West India

Posted – Mumbai

Company Profile – www.pumasports.com Product Deal: Sports Equipment Product Current CTC – 5.75 Lakhs (Indian Currency)

Job Responsibilities:

- Responsible for primary business for western part of India (Maharastra, Gujrat , Goa) .Looking after business thru Direct Dealer , wholesaler and Distributor
- Develop dealer distribution network and introduce distributor new dealer and retailer to boost up market as per needed
- Responsible for primary sales .
- Responsible for pricing scheme implement
- Responsible to handle 4 numbers sales team
- Responsible to sponsor local and regional players to utilized Slezenger Brand product
- Forecast sales for next month and rolling 2 month.
- Responsible to fix COD payment duration (There is separate credit duration for dealer 30 dayes to 45 days, (decided which dealer get how much credit period)
- Inventory monitor and control.
- Marketing activity
- Prepare Quarterly review meeting.
- Responsible to train newly joined and dealer sales person about product training, competitor product and price so that they can explain product to customer

3. USHA INTERNATIONAL LTD.

SEP

2009 till Nov 2013

Designation: Asst. Sales Manager

Posted

Guwahati Div. Sale Office : Sep 2009 to March 2011 Mumbai Div Sale Office : Since April' 11 till Nov 13

Working in Pune and Mumbai

Company Profile - www.ushainternational.com

Product Deal: Home Appliance **Current CTC – 4.8 Lakhs**

Job Responsibilities

- Develop dealer distribution network and introduce distributor new dealer and retailer to boost up market as per needed.
- Responsible for primary sales and collection target for the Branch.
- ❖ Focus on secondary for Distributor as well treachery sale for Retailer.
- Coordination with Head Office for DFS (Demand for Sales) / Material Movement till Goodown and Distributor and Modern Trade Store.
- ❖ Arrange sales promotion activities to directly attract customers. (ATL Activities)
- Reduced paperwork by integrating paperless office techniques with SAP Technology and Smart Phone
- Keeping track of competitors activities

Achievements

- ❖ Increased sales in North East India by 42.45 % and Get FTS Kazhakistan 2009
- ❖ Increased sales in South Maharashtra by 49 % and Get FTS to Sri Lanka 2011
- ❖ Increased sales in Central Mumbai by 39.41 % and Get Company spornship to attend MDTP (Management Devlopment Training program) by IIE at New Delhi 2013

4. HAVELLS INDIA LTD.

JUN 2005

to AUG 2009

Designation: Sr. Executive Sales & Marketing (Guwahati Branch)

Company Profile www.havells.com

Product Deal: Electrical Fan

Job Responsibilities

Trade Development (as mentioned above)

5. LG ELECTRONICS INDIA LTD.

APRIL. 2003-

MAY 2005

Designation: Sales Executive- Direct sales (Guwahati Branch)

Company Profile www.lg.com/in

Product Deal: RAC, HA, IT Product & CDP

Job Responsibilities

- Concentration on Direct sales to Govt./PSU / Corporate sales
- Create Customer profile

- * Responsible for preparing tender paper / Rate Contract approval
- ❖ Keeping track of competitors' activities
- * Responsible for collecting payment before due date.

EDUCATION

- ❖ Bachelor of Arts (English Language), 1999 (Guwahati University)
- ❖ MBA from Guwahati University 2003 (specialism at Sales and Marketing)
- ❖ 1 year Diploma in Basic Computer Application

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

❖ Traveling, Internet Surfing & Cricket

PERSONAL DETAILS

❖ Date of Birth : August 1, 1977

❖ Permanent Address: Yakub Ali Raod, (Near Art School) Santipur,

Nalbari, Assam

❖ Address : R 5/Flat No 108 Satyam CHS, RNA Plaza

Ram Mandir Road, Goregaon - W, Mumbai -62,

India

❖ Languages Known : English, Hindi, Assamese & Bengali